俄国边境的恐怖分子军火市场
A Terrorist Arms Bazaar on the Russian Border
我们的人在中央摄影机的位置
Our man's in position on the center camera.
这里好像恐怖分子的超级市场
It's like a terrorist supermarket.
中国的长征导弹，黑豹AS-565型攻击直升机…
Chinese Long March Scud, Panther AS-565 attack helicopter...
一对俄国迫击炮，那箱子看起来像是美国的步枪
a pair of Russian mortars, and the crates look like American rifles.
智利的地雷、德国的炸药，真是货式齐全
Chilean mines, German explosives. Fun for the whole family.
请辨识身分
I.D.s.
白骑士，给我们看看那些爪牙
White Rook to White Knight. Show us the pawns.
你看，他真的混进去了，将军，由中间那个人开始
You see, he did get through, Admiral. Start with that chap in the middle.
启动辨认身分的电脑程序
Load the I.D. Program, please.
搜寻身分资料库
Data base I.D. Search.
正在查询资料库
Checking the databases.
已找到第一个人，他是石原聪
We've got out first match. Satoshi Isagura.
化学专家，因东京地铁袭击事件被通缉
Chemical expert. Wanted for the Tokyo subway attack.
目前在非洲萨伊为叛军工作
Currently working for the insurgent force in Zaire.
亨利古达，美国人
Henry Gupta. American.
高科技恐怖主义的鼻祖
Practically invented techno-terrorism.
在60年代，他是柏克莱大学的激进学生
Started out as a student radical at Berkeley in the '60s.
现在他以出售恐怖主义谋生
Now he sells his politics for cash.
- 放大那个，可以吗？ - 好像是美国的编码器
- Zoom in on that, can you? - That looks like an American encoder.
用来控制全球定位导航卫星系统
They use it to control their navigation satellites: The G.P.S. System.
哪一样会令中央情报局生气
I wonder, will the C.I.A. Be more upset
他们失去它还是我们找到它？
that they lost it or that we found it?
对不起，将军
Excuse me. Admiral?
谢谢，M，我们看够了，该是军事行动的时候了
Thank you, M, we've seen enough. This is now a military operation.
看到那支盖特林机关枪吗？
You saw the Gatling gun?
你们的军队应付得来吗？
Are your troops prepared for that kind of firepower?
我们下星期将在莫斯科进行选举
We have election in Moscow next week.
总统不希望有士兵伤亡
The president said any loss of life is unacceptable.
我们会接受海军的提议
We'll take the naval option.
一次攻击就能消灭全球一半的恐怖分子
In one strike, we take out half the world's terrorists.
- 鲁巴克将军，我反对  - 联络柴斯特号
- Admiral Roebuck, I must protest. - Get me the Chester.
- 不要浪费时间 - 我的属下还没完成
- Best not waste time. - My man isn't finished.
黑将军呼叫白仕，可以发射了
Black King to White Bishop. Authorization to fire.
叫你的手下离开，他的工作已经完成
Get your man out of there. His job is over.
武器授权完成，准备发射导弹
Weapons authorized. Prepare to fire.
倒数计时，五、四、三、二、一
On my count. Five, four, three, two, one.
导弹已经发射
Missile away.
将于四分八秒后击中目标
Time to target: Four minutes, eight seconds.
白骑士，四分钟后爆炸，立即离开
White Knight, four minutes to impact. Get out of there.
我知道这是什么，就在我面前的荧幕里
Yes, damn it, I know what it is! It's on the screen in front of me.
是飞机前的吉普车
It's a jeep in front of a plane.
马上离开那里！
Now, get the hell out of there!
- 究竟发生什么事？ - 不能再等
- What the hell's going on? - You will not wait!
- 这是命令！ - 你的属下在等什么？
- That's an order! - What is your man waiting for?
白骑士？我的天
White Knight? Oh, my God!
那些是苏联SB-5核子鱼雷
Those are Soviet SB-5 nuclear torpedoes.
- 如果导弹击中这里… - 叫他们终止导弹攻击
- If the Cruise hits them... - Order them to abort the missile.
- 英国皇家柴斯特号，紧急情况 - 白骑士，请回答
- H.M.S. Chester urgent. - White Knight, come in.
终止导弹攻击…
Abort missile. Abort missile.
- 终止导弹攻击 - 终止导弹攻击
- Abort missile. - Abort missile.
长官，导弹已经太远了
Captain, sir, missile out of range.
我们无法摧毁导弹
Unable to destroy.
- 白骑士… - 通知北约跟美国国防部
- White Knight... - Alert NATO, the Pentagon.
- 导弹会引爆鱼雷吗？ - 可能会
- Will it trigger the torpedoes? - It might.
就算不会，那里的辐射…
But even if it does not, there's enough plutonium...
将会比切尔诺贝利核电厂的更多
to make Chernobyl look like picnic.
真糟糕！你们不能好好把东西锁起来吗？
Bloody hell! Can't you people keep anything locked up?
所有军队撤退，叫他立刻离开
Evacuate your troops, and get him out of there, now!
白骑士，请回答 白骑士，请回答！
White Knight, come in. White Knight, come in!
- 继续试，该死的！ - 白骑士，请回答
- Keep trying, damn it! - White Knight, come in.
重复，白骑士请回答
Repeat, White Knight, come in.
坏习惯
Filthy habit.
我拿到编码器了
I've got the encoder.
他在做什么？他在执行任务
- What the hell is he doing? - His job.
他要去抢鱼雷
He's going for the bombs.
去拿那吉普车
Get that jeep!
詹姆斯，快离开
Get out of it, James.
导弹一分钟后到达
One minute to impact.
导弹三十秒后到达
Thirty seconds to impact.
多事的砘
Backseat driver.
白骑士呼叫白车
White Knight to White Rook.
我已经安全撤退
I've evacuated the area.
问问将军，他想将鱼雷送到哪里
Ask the admiral where he'd like his bombs delivered.
片名：《明日帝国》
# Darling, I'm killed
# I'm in a puddle on the floor
# Waiting for you
# To return
# Oh, what a thrill
# Fascinations galore
# How you tease
# How you leave me to burn
# It's so deadly, my dear
# The power of having you near
# Until that day
# Until the world falls away
# Until you say
# There'll be no more good-byes
# I see it in your eyes
# Tomorrow never dies
# Darling, you've won It's no fun
# Martinis, girls and guns
# It's murder on our love affair
# But you bet your life every night
# While you're chasing the morning light
# You're not the only spy
# Out there
# It's so deadly, my dear
# The power of wanting you near
# Until that day
# Until the world falls away
# Until you say there'll be no more good-byes
# I see it in your eyes
# Tomorrow never dies
南中国海 英国皇家得文夏号
开动警报
Sound the general alarm.
两架中国米格机刚刚飞过上空
The ship has been overflown by two Chinese MiGs.
我们相信他们怀有敌意
We believe they have hostile intent.
准备作战
Hands to action stations.
英国皇家得文夏号，这是你们最后一次警告
H.M.S. Devonshire. This is your last warning.
你们已在中国领海
You are in Chinese territorial waters.
警戒员，全速航行，左转40度
Officer of the Watch, maximum speed. Come left 40 degrees.
是，长官，旋转速度160，转舵向左20度
Aye, aye, sir. Revolutions 1-6-0, port 20.
他们疯了吗？
Are they insane?
中国飞行员坚称我们离他们的海岸线11哩
The Chinese pilot insists that we are only 11 miles off their coast...
若不开进中国港口，他会开火
and he will fire if we don't turn around and go to a Chinese port.
回覆他：“我们在国际水域…”
Send this: "We are in international waters...
“如果受到袭击必会反击”
and will defend ourselves if attacked. "
将副本急送将军
Copy all this to the Admiralty, urgent.
我们肯定我们的方位吗？
Are we absolutely sure of our position?
肯定，是卫星定位
Yes, sir. An exact satellite fix.
汉堡卡佛媒体集团网络
Carver Media Group Network - Hamburg
我们已准备好发射
Captain, we are ready to launch.
关掉引擎
Shut down the engines.
保持静默
Maintain full silence.
雷达探测不到隐形船，但却可探测到海钻
A stealth ship may be invisible to radar but the Seadrill isn't.
米格机再飞过时便发射
We'll launch next time the MiGs fly by...
英国人会认为是中国的空中鱼雷
and the British will think it's a Chinese aerial torpedo.
我该去报告了
I should report in.
史丹博呼叫汉堡，第一步行动已经展开了
Stamper to Hamburg. Phase one is in progress.
晚点会再报告最新情况
I'll report back to you with an update.
- 米格机又来了 - 开始吧
- The MiGs are making another pass. - Let's start the show.
放下海钻
Seadrill in position.
开动海钻
Start the drill.
- 放出去 - 海钻放出了
- Release it. - Seadrill away.
绿色-30，有鱼雷…
Green 3-0, torpedo, torpedo, torpedo.
中央方位114
Center bearing 1-1-4.
警戒员，急右转141
Officer of the Watch, come hard right, 1-4-1.
声纳没有收到讯号，一定是米格机放下的
There's been no sonar contact, sir. The MiGs must have dropped it.
方位稳定，它会击中我们
Bearing steady. It's gonna hit, sir.
准备被撞击
Brace, brace, brace.
- 目标是1200 - 开门
- Target: 1200. - Knock knock.
到楼上去
Let's go upstairs.
- 左转 - 旋转90度
- Turn left. - Rotating 90 degrees.
他们正在猜为什么鱼雷没爆炸
Now they're wondering why the torpedo hasn't exploded.
全面损毁报告
PWO, Captain. Full damage report.
立即开动后备能量
Backup power, immediately!
开动替代能源
Switch to alternate supply.
三具发电机损毁，船尾第四层淹水
Three generators are down, sir. Flooding on four deck aft.
船头向下14度
Sir, we're now down 14 degrees by the stern.
通知将军：“遭中国米格机鱼雷击中，下沉中”
Yeoman, send to Admiralty: "Have been torpedoed by Chinese MiGs. Sinking. "
说出我们的方位，好的，弃船
Give them our position. Right. Abandon ship.
弃船！弃船！
Abandon ship! Abandon ship!
遭米格机鱼雷击中下沉中
全部上甲板
Everyone on deck! Come on!
对米格机发射一枚导弹
One missile at the MiGs.
保持无线电静默
Maintaining radio silence.
他们最后的发报
Their last broadcast, sir.
古达的编码器见效了
Mr. Gupta's little trick with the encoder worked.
他们报告最后的位置是离此70里
They gave their final position 70 miles from here.
英国海军永远找不到他们
The British Navy will never find them.
海面有生还者
Survivors in the water.
英国海军遇害
英国海军被谋杀
史丹博先生，我正在写标题
Mr. Stamper, I'm having fun with my headlines.
我需要知道生还者的正确数目
I need to know the exact number of survivors.
我开会要迟到了，确保用正确的子弹
Now, I'm late for a meeting. Make sure you use the right kind of ammunition.
知道
Yes, sir.
太美妙了
Delicious.
开始打捞行动
Start the recovery operation.
派潜水员到得文夏号
Send our divers down to the Devonshire.
导弹室
古达先生？已完成第一阶段
Mr. Gupta? Phase one is complete.
早安，忠心的员工
Good morning, my golden retrievers.
今天卡佛集团该为世界制造什么混乱呢？
What kind of havoc shall the Carver Media Group create in the world today?
- 新闻 - 巴基斯坦水灾，巴黎暴动
- News. - Floods in Pakistan, riots in Paris.
- 加州坠机 - 好极了
- And a plane crash in California. - Excellent.
琼斯先生，我们准备好推出新软件了吗？
Mr. Jones, are we ready to release our new software?
是的，如你的要求，有许多问题…
Yes, sir. As requested, it's full of bugs...
人们在未来会被迫将软件升级
which means people will be forced to upgrade for years.
了不起
Outstanding.
沃勒斯先生，打电话给总统
Mr. Wallace, call the president.
他如不签署降低有线电视收费的法案
Tell him if he doesn't sign the bill lowering the cable rates...
我们会播出他和啦啦队长鬼混的录影带…
we'll release a video of him with the cheerleader...
- 在芝加哥饭店… - 知道
- in the Chicago motel room. - Inspired, sir.
他签署后仍将录影带播出
After he signs the bill, release the tape anyway.
我一定会这么做
Consider him slimed.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
- 他在七号应答器 - 史丹博？
- He's on transponder seven. - Mr. Stamper?
开始第二阶段，我有录影带
Phase two is underway. I have the videotape.
我还没看过，但听说片段很精彩
I haven't seen it myself, but I'm told the footage is excellent.
还有17名生还者，可让你作标题
Plus, there were 17 survivors for your headlines.
干得好
Good work, Stamper.
- 谢谢你 - 不客气
- Thank you. - Don't mention it.
确保放在安全地方
Make sure you keep it in a safe place.
各位…
Gentlemen and ladies...
停止所有的印刷
hold the presses.
刚收到的
This just in.
在稀奇突发的命运下，今晚卫星新闻网络…
By a curious quirk of fate, we have the perfect story...
的首播有大新闻
with which to launch our Satellite News Network tonight.
南中国海好像正在耘酿一个小危机
It seems a small crisis is brewing in the South China Sea.
我要报章全面报导，杂志报导
I want full newspaper coverage. I want magazine stories.
书刊、电影、电视及电台广播
I want books. I want films. I want TV. I want radio.
我要我们24小时转播
I want us on the air 24 hours a day.
这是我们的时刻
This is our moment!
地球上有十亿人…
And a billion people around this planet...
会收看、收听…
will watch it, hear it...
和阅读由卡佛媒体集团报导的消息
and read about it from the Carver Media Group.
没有什么比得上坏消息了
There's no news like bad news.
邦德先生，我对你的进展很满意
I am pleased with your progress, Mr. Bond.
我一直都有兴趣学习新语言，教授
I've always enjoyed studying a new tongue, Professor.
你很有天分
One might say you have a natural ability.
但熟能生巧
But practice makes perfect.
丹麦话“我不在”怎么说？
How do you say "I'm not here" in Danish?
别管它
Just ignore it.
在他们的词汇里没有这些字
Those are words they just don't have in their vocabulary.
- 我是邦德 - 用安全线路，007
- Bond here. - Go to a secure line, 007.
用干扰器，第四频道
Going to a scrambler, channel four.
太荒谬了，他们在国际水域
That's ridiculous. That ship was in international waters.
- 我们不能肯定 - 詹姆斯？你在哪里？
- We can't be certain. - James? Where are you?
莫尼彭妮
Oh, Moneypenny.
我在牛津练习一下丹麦语
I'm just up here at Oxford brushing up on a little Danish.
一下？
Little?
恐怕你得跟你的课程吻别了
I'm afraid you're going to have to kiss off your lesson, James.
国防部有事
We've got a situation here at the Ministry of Defense.
要派舰队到中国
We're sending the fleet to China.
我一小时后到
I'll be there in an hour.
半小时吧
Make that 30 minutes.
再见，我的甜心
Good-bye, my sweet.
你一向都是口舌巧妙的语言家
You always were a cunning linguist, James.
- 别问 - 别说
- Don't ask. - Don't tell.
这太不合理了，我们知道军舰的正确方位
That's preposterous. We know exactly where that ship was positioned.
全球定位卫星不可能会出错
The G.P.S. System... Global Positioning Satellites... do not lie.
是的，但是新加坡控制中心在军舰受到攻击时…
Yes, but our Singapore station picked up a mysterious signal...
全球定位卫星截获了神秘的讯号
on the G.P.S. Frequency at the time of the attack.
那有可能让军舰偏离航道
It could've sent that ship off course.
- 英国巡洋舰失踪了 - 我知道
- I have a missing British frigate... - I'm aware of that!
你只想调查而不采取果断的行动
And instead of decisive action, all you want to do is investigate.
我希望避免第三次世界大战，而且我不认为…
My goal is to prevent World War Three, Admiral, and I don't think...
派舰队去寻找地点是最好的方法
sending an armada into the recovery area is the best way to do it.
那些神秘的全球定位卫星信号从哪里发出来的？
Where, exactly, did this mysterious G.P.S. Signal come from?
- 我们仍在调查  - “调查”
- We're still investigating. - "Investigating. "
M，我看你没种执行任务
M, sometimes I don't think you have the balls for this job.
或许吧，但是…
Perhaps, but the advantage is...
我从来都不用担心这个问题
I don't have to think with them all the time.
够了，现在的情形是如何？
That's enough. Now, where do we stand?
我们的军舰在国际水域受到无谓的攻击
It was an unprovoked attack on a ship in international waters.
我们派舰队去搜索跟准备反击
We send in the fleet for recovery and prepare for full retaliation.
用温和的作法展开我们的调查
Moderation. We investigate...
而不是派遣英国海军舰队…
and stop short of sending the entire British Navy...
进入世界最强大空军的领域内
within ten minutes of the world's largest air force.
- 我们的舰队何时能到达？  - 48小时
- When will our ships be in position? - Forty-eight hours.
我的天！
Christ!
报章已要求报复
The press are already screaming for blood.
我们不能让局势变得更紧张
The last thing we want to do is escalate the situation.
恐怕已经太迟了
I'm afraid it may be too late to worry about that.
17名英国海军被杀
Seventeen British sailors murdered!
“据发现尸体的越南官员宣称”
"According to Vietnamese officials who recovered the bodies...
“死者被中国空军子弹”
the victims were riddled with the same ammunition...
“打得满是窟窿”
used by the Chinese Air Force. "
- 是你泄露出去的吗？ - 不是
- Did you leak this? - No.
- 我第一次听到 - 就这样决定吧
- It's the first I've heard of it. - Well, this settles it.
我们派舰队去
We send in the fleet.
M，你有48小时的时间调查
M, you have 48 hours to investigate.
有件事很奇怪
There is one strange thing.
当我打电话给西贡的人员时，他说越南人…
When I called our contact in Saigon, he said the Vietnamese...
在三小时前才发现海军的尸体
only found our sailors three hours ago.
报纸怎会这么快就刊出？
How'd they get the paper out so fast?
明日报的人比越南政府更早知道
Somebody at Tomorrow knew before the Vietnamese government did.
你知道多少艾利欧卡佛的事？
How much do you know about Elliot Carver, 007?
全球媒体大亨
Worldwide media baron.
可藉报导推翻政府
Able to topple governments with a single broadcast.
明日报是卡佛的
Carver owns that newspaper Tomorrow.
我不想在部长面前讨论这件事
I didn't want to discuss it in front of the minister...
那些神秘信号来自卡佛的其中一个卫星
but that mysterious signal came from one of Carver's satellites.
如果首相知道你在调查他，一定会杀了我
The P.M. Would have my head if he knew you were investigating him.
007，我派你去汉堡，我们已经安排好
I'm sending you to Hamburg, 007. We've arranged for you to be invited...
你受邀参加卡佛媒体集团的酒会
to a party at Carver's Media Center.
他们庆祝发射新卫星
They're celebrating the launch of a new satellite...
因为他现在有能力将消息传播到世界的每个角落
because now he has the ability to reach every human being on the Earth.
但是中国拒绝给他广播权
Except the Chinese, who have refused broadcast rights.
你的机票，掩护的身分跟租车预约的收据
Your ticket, cover story and rental car reservation.
请签名
Sign here, please.
我记得你曾跟卡佛的太太有过一段情
I believe you once had a relationship with Carver's wife, Paris.
那已是陈年往事
That was a long time ago, M...
在她结婚之前
before she was married.
我不晓得原来是众所周知的
I didn't realize it was public knowledge.
请以国家为重，詹姆斯
Queen and country, James.
你的责任是要找出是否卡佛或他的下属…
Your job is to find out whether Carver or someone in his organization...
让军舰偏离航道，还有他这样做的原因
sent that ship off course and why.
尽量利用你跟卡佛太太的关系
Use your relationship with Mrs. Carver if necessary.
我很怀疑她还记不记得我
I doubt if she'll remember me.
那就去提醒她
Remind her.
从她身上刺探出消息
Then pump her for information.
你只要决定如何刺探出消息
You'll just have to decide how much pumping is needed, James.
莫尼彭妮，如果我跟你是这样就好了
If only that were true of you and I, Moneypenny.
明日报：中国警告英国舰队
请你在这里签名，邦德先生
If you'll just sign here, Mr. Bond.
这是你漂亮的新车的…
It's the insurance damage waiver...
保险损毁豁免书
for your beautiful new car.
- 你需要碰撞保险吗？ - 需要
- Will you need collision coverage? - Yes.
火险呢？
Fire?
可能需要
Probably.
- 财物保险呢？ - 当然要
- Property destruction? - Definitely.
伤亡保险呢？
Personal injury?
希望不要，但意外有时难以避免
I hope not, but accidents do happen.
只要有你，意外是跑不掉
They frequently do with you.
这样应该可以了吧
Well, that takes care of the normal wear and tear.
我还需要其他的保护吗？
Do I need any other protection?
如果你弄坏车子，我会修理你
Only from me, 007, unless you bring that car back in pristine order.
- 你先请 - 你先请
- Shall we? - Shall we?
你的新宝马750
Your new BMW 750.
做了一般精细的设备，有机关枪，火箭炮…
All the usual refinements... machine guns, rockets...
全球卫星定位系统
the G.P.S. Tracking system.
欢迎，请系上安全带，遵照指示以确保安全
Welcome. Please fasten seat belt and obey all instructions for a safe trip.
我想你比较注意女性的声音
I thought you'd pay more attention to a female voice.
- 我想我们见过面了 - 我对你那些…
- I think we've met. - I am not interested...
脏脏的恶作剧没什么兴趣
in your sordid escapades.
让我们继续吧，好吗？
Let's get on with it, shall we?
你的新电话
Your new telephone.
听跟说都是这里
Talk here, listen here.
所以这几年我都做错了
So that's what I've been doing wrong all these years.
它还有指纹扫瞄…
It also includes a fingerprint scanner...
跟两万瓦的保全系统
and a 20,000-volt security system.
还有我最得意的…
And this I'm particularly proud of...
你车子的遥控器
the remote control for your car.
压两次
Tap twice.
一，二
One, two.
移动你的手指
Now, draw your finger...
慢慢地划过垫子…
very slowly across the pad...
来开车
to drive the car.
做起来有点困难但经过练习…
It's surprisingly difficult to drive, but with practice...
我们来看看她对我的触摸有什么反应？
Well, let's see how she responds to my touch, eh, Q?
我们很了解彼此
I think we understand each other.
别那么幼稚了，007
Grow up, 007.
注意，车子仍开动，请关上门
Attention. Engine running. Please shut door now.
别让她玩得团团转
Don't let her push you around.
这些恶意的谣言完全不正确
Anyway, there's absolutely no truth in this malicious rumor...
竟然说是我开始报导狂牛病事件
that I started running Mad Cow Disease stories...
是因为英国的牛肉大王安格斯布拉克爵士…
simply because Sir Angus Black, the great British beef baron...
在牌局中输给我一万镑，最后又不认帐
lost 10,000 pounds to me in a game of poker and refused to pay up.
另一个谣言更不正确
Moreover, there's even less truth in the rumor...
说法国给我一亿法郎
that I took 100 million francs from the French...
要我在未来的一年中继续报导这则新闻
to keep the stories running for another year.
- 打扰了，卡佛先生 - 是的
- Excuse me, Mr. Carver. - Yes.
这是新来的银行家
This is the new banker, Mr...
詹姆斯邦德
Bond. James Bond.
另一个新银行家，我好像在收集他们
Another new banker. I seem to collect them.
请告诉我，邦德先生
Tell me, Mr. Bond.
市场对这次危机的反应如何？
How's the market reacting to the crisis?
货币下跌，你们公司的股票正在上升
Well, currencies are off. Your stock is soaring.
我们以前没见过
I don't believe we have met.
- 我是艾利欧卡佛 - 我是林葳
- Elliot Carver. - Wai Lin.
我在中国新华社工作
I'm from the New China News Agency.
我没在宾客名单看到你的名字
I don't recall seeing your name on the guest list.
坦白说
I have a confession.
我是偷溜进来的
It's not. I snuck in.
你为什么要这么做，亲爱的？
Why would you do that, my dear?
我想见你
I wanted to meet you.
非常好
Outstanding.
我欣赏主动的女人
I admire a woman who takes the initiative.
- 你该在我的北京分社工作 - 卡佛先生
- You should work in my Beijing bureau. - Mr. Carver.
- 你在北京没有分社 - 叫我艾利欧就可以
- You don't have a bureau in Beijing. - Call me Elliot.
我一直好奇再次见到你会是什么感觉？
I always wondered how I'd feel if I ever saw you again.
现在我知道了
Now I know.
是我说了什么吗？
Was it something I said?
对“我马上回来”这句话有印象吗？
How about the words, "I'll be right back?"
- 突然有事 - 你总是突然有事
- Something came up. - Something always came up.
- 你好吗？帕莉丝 - 现在好多了，我们扯平了
- And how are you, Paris? - Much better now. We're even.
你要喝点什么吗？卡佛太太
Something to drink, Mrs. Carver?
给邦德先生一杯用摇的不是用搅的伏特加马汀尼
Mr. Bond will have a vodka martini, shaken not stirred.
卡佛太太要一杯纯龙舌兰酒
Mrs. Carver will have a tequila, straight shot.
不，卡佛太太要一杯卡佛先生的香槟
No, Mrs. Carver will have a glass of Mr. Carver's champagne.
看来你的身分提高了不少
I see you've moved up in the world, Paris.
今晚你是个银行家，我看到宾客名单
And tonight, you're a banker. I saw the guest list.
你睡觉时仍将枪放在枕头下吗？
Tell me, James, do you still sleep with a gun under your pillow?
- 敬你 - 不，敬你的枪
- To you. - No, to the gun.
我想你不是为社交活动来的吧？
So I take it this isn't a social visit?
你先生可能有麻烦
Your husband may be in trouble.
他是传播界之王
The emperor of the air.
如果你认为可以捉到他，那你才有麻烦
If you think you're going after him, you're the one who's in trouble.
或许吧，但不是他就是他的属下
Perhaps, but it's either him or someone in his organization.
原来如此，你以为能从我这儿得到线索
I see. And you figured you could charm the dirt out of me.
不，那不是我的计划
No. That wasn't my plan.
很好，如果要我在…
Good. Because if it comes to a choice...
你们之中选择，我已做了抉择
between you and Elliot, I've made my bed.
你已被三振出局
You don't sleep in it anymore.
原来你在这里
There you are.
亲爱的
Darling.
我到处找你
I've been looking everywhere for you.
我想让你见见林葳，她在新华社工作
I want you to meet Wai Lin, New China News Agency.
- 你好，卡佛太太 - 很荣幸认识你
- Hello, Mrs. Carver. - It's a pleasure.
这是詹姆斯邦德
And this is James Bond.
我不知道你们认识
I didn't realize you knew each other.
- 我们是老朋友 - 泛泛之交
- We're old friends. - Casual acquaintances.
他在苏黎世时是我室友的男友
He dated my roommate in Zurich.
我想雇用林葳小姐
I'm thinking of getting Wai Lin behind a news desk.
那太好了，我想她一定不会…
That's wonderful. I'm sure she won't resist...
拒绝
too much.
告诉我，我在想着关于你的卫星
Tell me, Elliot, I was just wondering about your satellites...
你在全球部署的方式
the way you've positioned yourself globally.
它们只是用来广播资讯
They're merely tools for information, Mr. Bond.
也可能是虚假资讯
Or disinformation.
例如，你能用卫星去干扰政府或人们
Say, if you wanted to manipulate the course of governments or people.
甚至是一艘船
Or even a ship.
真有趣，邦德先生
That's very interesting, Mr. Bond.
作为一个银行家，你的想像力非常丰富
You have a vivid imagination for a banker.
或许我该委任你写小说
Perhaps I should commission you to write a novel.
不行，我会迷失在大海中，漂流
Oh, heavens, no. I'd be lost at sea. Adrift.
开幕的时间到了
It's time to begin the festivities.
失陪一下，亲爱的？
Excuse me. Darling?
你怎么认识他的？
So, how do you really know him?
我已说了，他是个银行家，我们在苏黎世认识的
I told you, he's a banker. I met him in Zurich.
你说谎的技巧很差
You're a terrible liar, dear.
我看那个银行家不顺眼
I have a problem with a banker.
你可否跟我来一下？
Could I see you a moment?
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen.
卡佛先生十分钟后会在大厅开始致词
Mr. Carver's broadcast will be starting in ten minutes in the main studio.
你擅长哪方面的银行业务？
Exactly what kind of banking do you specialize in, Mr. Bond?
敌意收购，我们走吧？
Hostile takeovers. Shall we?
卡佛在这里一定感觉像在家一样
Carver must feel at home in a room like this.
能够对着全世界说话真好
It's nice to talk to the world.
看起来有人想跟你谈谈
Looks like there's someone who wants to talk to you.
邦德先生，你有一通紧急电话
Mr. Bond, you have an urgent phone call.
各位，五秒后现场播出，五
Ladies and gentlemen, we are live in five...
四，三，二…
four, three, two...
晚安
Good evening.
今晚的广播应该是个庆典
Tonight's broadcast was supposed to be a celebration...
显示卡佛全球卫星网络的完成
marking the completion of the Carver Global Satellite Network.
但你们知道
But, as you're well aware...
南中国海出现冲突
a terrible conflict looms tonight in the South China Sea...
不加制止的话
which, unchecked...
可能会毁灭地球上每一个人
has the potential to destroy every human being on Earth.
- 我想向观众保证，我… - 这边请
- I want to assure my viewers that I... - This way, please.
艾利欧卡佛跟英首相…
Elliot Carver, have spoken with the prime minister in London...
及在北京的主席谈过
and the chairman in Beijing...
提出我作为不偏不倚的…
and have offered my services as an impartial...
这房间有隔音设备，没人会听到你的叫声
It's a soundproof room, Mr. Bond. Nobody hears you scream.
史丹博，我们已接头了
Herr Stamper, we have made contact.
好好对付他
Make him uncomfortable.
我待会儿就来
I'll be there in a few moments.
24小时刊印新闻
...with its printing presses that run 24 hours a day...
卫星联系每一个…
and its satellite facilities linking every last...
你好像很关心卡佛先生的生意
You seem very concerned about Mr. Carver's business.
他想知道原因
He wants to know why.
你们问我为何这么做
Why did I do it, you ask.
答案很简单，权力
The answer is simple: Power.
启发地球偏远地区的人权力
The power to illuminate the far corners of the globe.
不为利润
Not for higher profits...
而是促进人与人之间的了解
but for higher understanding between the people of this great planet.
让他坐在椅子上，我们在他头上玩点把戏
Put him in the chair. Maybe we play a little number on his head.
我想得到什么回报？
And what do I expect in return?
支配全球
Worldwide domination.
完完全全，彻底的支配全球
Complete, utter, total worldwide domination.
但不是凌驾政府或意识形态
But not over governments or ideology.
是凌驾暴政，隔绝及无知
Over tyranny and isolation and ignorance.
卡佛媒体集团有能力
The Carver Media Group Network has the ability...
接触每一个人，在每个村庄，每个国家
to reach every person in every village in every nation.
但别感到害怕
But do not fear me...
我今晚提出的原则宣言
for tonight I offer you my declaration of principles:
承诺地球上每一个男女
A promise to the men and women of this planet...
我所服务的兄弟姐妹
my brothers and sisters whom I so humbly serve.
不偏不倚，没有恐惧的报导新闻
I promise to report the news without fear or favor.
我承诺作为这世上的善良力量
I promise to be a force for good in this world...
反抗不公正，压倒偏执
fighting injustice, crushing intolerance...
向不人道宣战
battling inhumanity.
该是…
It's time for...
广播中断的时候了
a station break.
- 怎么了？ - 我们失去了电力
- What's happening? - We've lost power.
- 广播中断 - 什么？
- We're off the air. - What?
各位，请保持冷静，不用离去
Ladies and gentlemen, please stay calm. There's no need to go for the exit.
几分钟后会恢复电力
We will go on in a few minutes' time.
什么意思，你不知道？你被开除了！滚！
What do you mean, you don't know? You're fired! Get out of my sight!
颇令人尴尬的…
And, in a rather embarrassing note...
好战的媒体巨子卡佛今晚在全球的…
scrappy media mogul Elliot Carver was cut off the air tonight...
卫星网络首播致词时
in mid-speech during the inaugural broadcast...
被半途中断
of his Worldwide Satellite Network.
很抱歉，艾利欧，不是我们做的
Sorry, Elliot, but we didn't do it.
很光彩的晚上，不是吗？
Glorious evening, wasn't it?
别管那些人
Come on, Elliot. Ignore those people.
- 这种事常常会发生 - 不会在我身上的
- Sometimes these things happen. - Not to me.
不会在我身上的
Not to me!
我16岁时在香港一间报社工作
When I was 16, I went to work for a newspaper in Hong Kong.
是间小报社，但编辑教导了我最重要的事
It was a rag, but the editor taught me one important lesson.
出色的报导，关键不在于人物
The key to a great story is not who...
内容或时间
or what or when...
而是原因
but why.
你的朋友邦德先生把今晚搞砸了
Your friend, Mr. Bond, made a mess tonight.
- 我想知道原因 - 我已说了，我跟他是泛泛之交
- I want to know why. - I told you, I barely know him.
泛泛之交？
Barely?
我正在好奇卡佛先生会派谁来
I was curious who Carver would send.
他要对付你
He's on to you.
我们都知道你站在谁那边
Well, we know where you stand.
你已做了抉择
You made your bed.
我正站在你的房门口
I'm standing in your doorway.
你可以转身回家了
Then turn around and go home.
告诉他从我这儿套不出什么
You can tell him you didn't get anything out of me.
就这样？回家去？
That's it? Go home?
我并没有要你牵涉这件事
I didn't ask you to get involved in this.
已经太迟了
It's too late for that.
你为何要嫁给他？
Why did you marry him?
他说他爱我
He told me he loved me.
这话很中听
That always sounds good.
我曾每天看报纸找你的仆闻
Do you know I used to look in the papers every day for your obituary?
抱歉，我令你失望了
Well, I'm sorry I keep disappointing you.
到底是为什么？
What was it, James?
我太接近吗？
Did I get too close?
近到让你不舒服？
Did I get too close for comfort?
是的
Yes.
我想念你
I missed you.
你查到什么？
What did you find?
我黑入银行的电脑，他们在使用SSL2…
I hacked into the mainframe at the bank. They're using an SSL2 encryption...
省掉这段高科技词汇
Spare me the technobabble, please.
邦德有完美的受雇记录，十年
Bond's got a perfect employment record. Ten years.
他做事非常小心谨慎
He's crossed every "T," he's dotted every "I."
- 什么意思？ - 是政府的情报员
- Which means? - Government agent.
我称之为古达创意异例定律
I call it Gupta's Law of Creative Anomalies.
若是毫无破绽的，定有问题
If it sounds too good to be true, it always is.
你认为我老婆知道吗？
Do you think my wife knows?
太多杂音，但若调低四周的声音…
There's a lot of garbage, but if you dial down the ambient noise...
你睡觉时仍将枪放在枕头下吗？
Tell me, James, do you still sleep with a gun under your pillow?
再来一次
Play it again.
你睡觉时仍将枪放在枕头下吗？
Tell me, James, do you still sleep with a gun under your pillow?
我想该安排她跟医生见面了
I think we should set an appointment for my wife with the doctor.
- 我必须走了 - 不，你不必
- I have to go. - No, you don't.
我可以让你在四小时内离开这个国家
I can get you out of the country in four hours.
我别无选择
I have no choice.
没人可以保护我免遭他毒手，连你都不行
No one can protect me from him, not even you.
- 你有选择 - 除非你放过他
- You do have a choice. - Only if you let him go.
我办不到
I can't do that.
他在顶层有个秘密实验室，甚至连我都不应该知道
He has a secret lab on the top floor even I'm not supposed to know about.
在屋顶有个紧急天窗
There's an emergency hatch on the roof.
- 你不必告诉我 - 那是最容易进去的地方
- You don't have to do this. - It's the easiest way to get in.
别跟我争辩
Don't argue with me, James.
你知道吗…
You know...
你的这个工作…
this job of yours...
是个感情上的致命武器
it's murder on relationships.
我不在的这段时间，派两个人…
Until I get back next week, I want two guards...
每天24小时在外面守卫
outside this office 24 hours a day.
谁也不能够进来
Nobody gets in. Got it?
我们会处理
We'll take care of it.
卫星怎么办？
What do we do with the satellite?
送到发射站，小心点
Send this thing off to the launch site. And be careful.
它值三亿元，你打破了它，你就要买下来
It's worth 300 million dollars. You break it, you bought it. Understand?
我讨厌旅行，从来都不知道要打包什么
I hate travelling. I never know what to pack.
在找寻新的题材吗？
Looking for a news story?
现在他们什么都印
They'll print anything these days.
哪位？
Yes?
早安，邦德先生，我是卡佛
Good morning, Mr. Bond. Elliot Carver.
我相信你拿走两件属于我的东西
I believe you've got two items that belong to me.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
红色的盒子，邦德先生
The red box, Mr. Bond...
还有我老婆在你饭店的房间
and my wife in your hotel room.
他来了
He's coming.
指纹身分已被确认
Fingerprint I.D. Accepted.
请选择保全程度
Please select security system level.
你如果找到编码器便通知我
Tell me if you find the encoder.
- 立刻打电话给我 - 好
- Call me immediately. - Yeah.
最新消息
And in breaking news...
我们伤心的宣布帕莉丝卡佛的死讯
it is with great sadness that we announce the death of Paris Carver...
她自成为卡佛太太后
who has become an international figure since she became the wife...
名闻国际
of Elliot Carver, chairman of this network.
德国汉堡警方表示
According to police officials in Hamburg, Germany...
她今早被发现
Mrs. Carver was found dead this morning...
倒毙在饭店套房，死因异常
in a hotel suite in that city in unusual circumstances...
警方拒绝进一步透露详情
on which police have refused to elaborate.
法医验尸在三天后…
A coroner has been called for and is expected to deliver...
会有全面报告
his full report within the next three days.
她身旁有一个不知名男子的尸体
Her body was discovered along with the body of an unidentified man...
相信他是吞枪自杀
who appeared to be the victim of a self-inflicted gun wound.
在他的私人飞机上联络到他…
Reached aboard his private jet en route...
我已经瞄准你的头，邦德先生
I have a clear shot at your head, Mr. Bond.
慢慢的站起来
Stand up, slowly.
扔下枪将它踢过来给我
Drop your gun and kick it toward me, ja?
警方拒绝猜测…
At present, police have refused to speculate...
这宗杀人跟自杀的动机
on a motive in this murder/suicide.
好的，现在…
Good. Now...
躺在卡佛太太身旁
lie down on the bed next to Mrs. Carver.
我们向卡佛先生致深切慰问
We extend our deepest sympathies to Mr. Carver.
一小时后会有报导
This story will be on the news in an hour.
- 今天的明日报新闻 - 没错
- Tomorrow's news today. - Just so.
我是高夫曼医生
My name is Dr. Kaufman.
是一名出色的神枪手
I am an outstanding pistol marksman.
请相信我，好吗？
Take my word for it, ja?
拿长柄大锤过来
Get the sledgehammers.
她很奋力的反抗
She struggled terribly, Mr. Bond.
你不该将她牵涉入此事
It's a pity you got her involved in all this.
你从那儿开枪杀我就不像是自杀
It won't look like a suicide if you shoot me from over there.
我是法医学教授
I am a professor of forensic medicine.
相信我，就算我从远方射杀你…
Believe me, Mr. Bond, I could shoot you from Stuttgart...
也可以有自杀的效果
and still create the proper effect.
我的技术很受欢迎
My art is in great demand, Mr. Bond.
世界各地都有人雇用我
I go all over the world.
我擅长使名人服食过量药物死亡
I am especially good at the celebrity overdose.
但恐怕我们的…
But now, I'm afraid, Mr. Bond, that our little...
史丹博，别在我的耳朵大叫，好吗？
Stamper! Stop yelling in my ear, ja?
他们打不开车门
Sir, they can't get into the car.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
- 有找过汽车拖吊所吗？ - 你要打电话给他们吗？
- Did you call the Auto Club? - Do you want to call them?
逼他说出如何打开车门
Make him tell you how to open it.
好，我来问
Okay, I ask.
这真难为情
This is very embarrassing.
好像有个红盒子在你车上
It seems there is a red box in your car.
他们无法打开车门
They can't get to it.
他们要我逼你打开车门
They want me to make you unlock the car.
我感觉像个白痴，不知道应该说什么
I feel like an idiot. I don't know what to say.
若你不听话，我就折磨你
I am to torture you if you don't do it.
- 你也是这方面的博士？ - 不…
- You've a doctorate in that too? - No, no, no.
算是个嗜好，但我很有天分
This is more like a hobby. But I'm very gifted.
我相信你
Oh, I believe you.
- 我的手机可以打开车门 - 不，邦德先生
- My cell phone opens the car. - No, Mr. Bond.
让我来，好吗？
I do it, ja?
重拨，再按三，然后送出
Recall, three, send.
等一下
Wait.
我是职业杀手，只是收钱办事
I'm just a professional doing a job.
我也是
Me too.
高夫曼医生
Dr. Kaufman.
欢迎，请系上安全带
Welcome. Please fasten seat belt.
减速
Reduce speed.
有行人在路上
Pedestrians in roadway.
司机请小心
Driver alert.
前面有障碍，请马上减速
Obstruction ahead. Reduce speed now.
请注意，鲁莽驾驶将使保证无效
Reminder: Unsafe driving will void warranty.
恭喜你一路平安
Congratulations on a safe journey.
南中国海美国空军基地
U.S. Air Base, South China Sea
詹姆斯
Yo! Jimbo!
韦德，你为什么会在这里？
Wade, what are you doing here?
你知道我是四海为家的，走这边吧
You know the world's my office. Let's go this way.
Q博士有跟你解释清楚吗？
Did Q bring you up to speed?
有，我已经带了全球定位卫星的校准仪器来
Yeah. I brought along the G.P.S. Calibration unit.
顺便跟你提一下，正式来说，美国在这次行动是中立的
By the way, officially Uncle Sam is completely neutral in this turkey shoot.
非正式呢？
And unofficially?
除非是美国先开战，否则我们不希望看到世界大战
We have no interest in seeing World War Three, unless we start it.
格林渥特博士是定位卫星的专家
Dr. Greenwalt. He's the Air Force G.P.S. Expert.
很抱歉，保安那么严密
Sorry about all this security...
定位卫星的编码器…
but the G.P.S. Encoder is one of the most closely guarded secrets...
是美国军方的最高机密
in the U.S. Military.
让他看看你有什么
Show him what you got.
我的天，这是失去了的编码器，你怎样拿到的？
Jesus, it's the missing encoder. How the hell did you get that?
昨天早上在汉堡找到的
Picked it up in Hamburg yesterday morning.
它可以使船舰偏离航道吗？
Could somebody use this to send a ship off course?
- 你指的是得文夏号？ - 别瞎猜
- Like the Devonshire? - Whoa!
没人说过得文夏号，是吗？
I didn't you hear anybody mention the Devonshire. Did you?
- 是 - 那你快回答他的问题
- No. - Good. So just answer his question.
理论上，如果你能影响计时芯片
In theory, if you could alter the timing chip...
你就可以使船舰偏离航道
you could slowly send a ship off course.
- 好像在指南针旁边放置磁铁 - 没错
- Like putting a magnet near a compass. - Yeah, exactly.
- 请你检查一下这个 - 好的
- Then check this out. - Oh, yeah.
这两个圆圈是应该重叠的
Those two circles should be lining up on top of each other.
有人曾经改动过编码器
Somebody's tampered with your encoder.
如果知道得文夏号最后显示的时间和位置
If we knew the last time and position the Devonshire thought she was...
你能够找出它沉没的地点吗？
could you figure out exactly where she sank?
当然可以
Sure.
韦德
Wade...
我要请你帮个小忙
I have a small favor to ask.
高空起跳、低空张伞…
The high-altitude, low opening jump... the HALO jump...
是最易致命的，所以请听清楚
is where we get the most fatalities, so listen up.
你自由下降五英里和要使用氧气，否则你会窒息而死
You free-fall for 5 miles and use your oxygen, or you'll die of asphyxiation.
就像我的第一段婚姻
Sounds like my first marriage.
自由下降之后…
After the free-fall...
在离地二百尺时打开降落伞，那能避开中国的雷达
pop the chute at 200 feet, below the Chinese radar.
你的时速将会超过二百英里
You'll be traveling at over 200 miles an hour.
风力随时能扭断你的脖子
This snaps your head back like a cantaloupe.
头部别撞到氧气筒
Don't crack your skull open on the tanks.
我会紧记着
I'll keep that in mind.
最后，当你到达水面就马上切断降落伞
One last thing: When you hit the water don't forget to cut away your chute.
百分之九十进行这种跳法的人都被降落伞缠着而溺毙
90% of people killed in the HALO jump got tangled in their chutes and drowned.
明白吗？
Got it?
为了拯救世界，要做的事情可真不少
Seems like a lot just to save the world.
我没有别的选择
I've got no choice.
我要证明军舰是被故意引离航道
I have to prove that ship was deliberately set off course.
一分钟
One minute!
- 安排好接应了吗？ - 当然
- Is the pickup set? - You bet.
完成任务之后就把无线电开着，我们会来接应你
After your mission, turn on your beacon. The extraction team will pick you up.
祝你好运
Buddha bless!
- 我刚刚发现… - 什么？
- I just noticed something. - Yeah?
这里是军舰误认的地点
This is where the ship thought it was.
这里是军舰真正的地点，看到这个岛吗？
This is where it really is. But see that island?
- 是的 - 他将要降落的地方
- Yeah. - That means where he's jumping...
刚好在英国跟中国的舰队中间
between the British and Chinese fleets...
严格来说，这里不是中国的领海
Technically they're not in Chinese territorial waters.
- 这里其实是越南的领海 - 越南的？
- They belong to Vietnam. - Vietnam?
他身上有美国政府的标记吗？
Does he have any U.S. Government markings on him?
降落伞、潜水衣、蛙鞋全都有
The parachute, the wet suit, the fins.
如果越南人捉到他，他们会发疯的
If the Vietnamese catch him, they're gonna go crazy.
他不辞而别
He didn't even say good-bye.
对敌意收购有兴趣吗？
Still interested in hostile takeovers?
我最喜欢当银行家可以到处旅行
It's the opportunities for travel that I like best about banking.
开过来这边
Bring the boat.
你还在等什么？
What are you waiting for?
带他们上来
Get them out of the water.
若是不知道，还以为你在跟踪我
If I didn't know better, I'd say you were following me around, Mr. Bond.
你也得承认…
You'll have to admit, though...
我们似乎发展了密不可分的关系
we seem to have developed a certain attachment to each other.
希望只是暂时的
Hopefully not for long.
另一幢卡佛的大厦
Another Carver building.
若是不知道，我还以为他开发了一整片的摩天大厦
If I didn't know better, I'd say he'd developed an edifice complex.
张将军？你的朋友？
General Chang? Friend of yours?
邦德先生，林小姐
Mr. Bond. Miss Lin.
欢迎来到西贡市
Welcome to Saigon.
真高兴又看到你，艾利欧
It's always nice to see you, Elliot.
我准备在明天启用这幢大厦
I hadn't intended opening this center until tomorrow...
你现在来到，刚好可以帮我写开幕故事
but as you're here you can help me to write the inaugural story...
就是你的仆文
your obituaries.
希望你对帕莉丝也这么好
I hope you extended the same courtesy to Paris.
其实当你叫我已故的太太出卖我时…
Actually, Mr. Bond, you're the one who wrote my late wife's obituary...
你已经为她写了仆文
when you asked her to betray me.
没关系，让我们看看…
Still, let's see...
“英国情报员詹姆斯邦德”
"British secret service agent James Bond...
“跟中国情报员”
and his collaborator Wai Lin...
“林葳小姐”
of the Chinese People's External Security Force...
“在今天早晨”
were found...
“被发现…”
dead this morning...
“死于越南”
in Vietnam. "
太平淡了，是吗？
Lacks punch, don't you think?
这已不是新闻，我跟她合作几个月了
It's old news, Elliot. We've been working together for months.
我们两国政府都知道你跟张将军的勾当
Both our governments know what you and General Chang are up to.
我看不是
I don't think so.
你们也许在走廊看到张将军
You may have seen the general in the hallway just now...
但是你们可能太忙吧
but perhaps, with all your jetting around...
未看到今天的头条新闻
you've not had chance to peruse today's headlines.
我最喜欢这一句，这还不是我的报纸呢
I rather like the last one. It isn't even mine.
我从不相信报纸的新闻
I never believe what I read in the press anyway.
这就是你的问题，邦德先生
Ah. Therein lies your problem, Mr. Bond.
我们都是能干的人，但你跟林小姐的时代已成过去
We're both men of action, but your era and Miss Lin's is passing.
现在，文字就是力量，卫星就是武器
Words are the new weapons, satellites the new artillery.
而你就是世界联盟的最高统帅？
And you become the new supreme allied commander?
完全对！
Exactly!
凯撒跟拿破仑都有自己的军队
Caesar had his legions, Napoleon had his armies...
而我也有我的队伍… 电视、报纸、杂志
I have my divisions... TV, news, magazines.
到今晚午夜，收听到我广播的人…
And by midnight I'll have reached and influenced more people...
将是前所未见的多，除了上帝
than anyone in the history of this planet, save God Himself.
就算上帝也只是在山上讲道罢了
And the best He ever managed was the Sermon on the Mount.
你真的疯了
You really are quite insane.
疯子跟天才的差别…
The distance between insanity and genius...
也不过是成功与失败
is measured only by success.
对不起
Excuse me.
张将军在等你
General Chang is waiting.
很抱歉
If you'll forgive me,
你们的出现逼得我…
your appearance here has forced me...
得把时间表提早一点
to move up my timetable slightly.
我将你们交给史丹博跟他的玩具处理
I'll leave you in the capable hands of Mr. Stamper and his toys.
或许你们想看看
Perhaps you'd like to see them.
直升机正在等
Sir. The helicopter.
谢谢，古达
Thanks, Gupta.
已故的史丹博是高夫曼医生的徒弟
Mr. Stamper is a protege of the late Dr. Kaufman...
高夫曼医生教授他古代的折磨艺术
who was schooling him in the ancient art of chakra torture.
他就像我的父亲一样
He was like a father to me.
真的？很有趣的榜样
Really? Interesting role model.
根据东方的哲学，人体有七个要穴
According to Eastern philosophy, the body has seven chakra points.
它们是身体的能量中心，例如心脏或是性器官
Energy centers, like the heart or genitals.
这些工具是用来刺进那些器官的
The purpose of these implements is to probe those organs...
让痛苦达到极限
inflicting the maximum amount of pain...
而又能让受害者存活久一点
whilst keeping the victim alive for as long as possible.
高夫曼的纪录是52小时
Dr. Kaufman's record was 52 hours.
我希望能打破它
I'm hoping to break it.
我以为看你的节目已是虐待了
Hmm. I would've thought watching your TV shows was torture enough.
这个留到最后
Save this one till last.
当你拿出邦德的心脏时
When you remove Mr. Bond's heart...
应该还有时间，让他看着自己的心脏停止跳动
there should be just enough time for him to watch it stop beating.
失陪了
Excuse me.
快走…
Go! Go! Go! Go!
我们能利用大型海报
We can use the banner.
希望可以支撑得了
Hope it holds.
- 快去追他们！ - 准备好没有？走
- Get after them! - Ready? Go!
下次我会搭电梯
Next time I'll take the elevator.
用力推…
Push! Push!
- 找部车来！ - 不…
- Get a car! - No, no!
- 是的，找车！ - 摩托车快一点
- Yes, a car! - A bike is quicker.
有钥匙，总是有人忘记
The keys. Someone always forgets them.
你在干嘛？我来骑，下来
What are you doing? I'm driving. Get off.
你坐后面
Get on the back.
我在滑下去
I'm slipping.
别在后面动来动去
Stop fidgeting back there.
你在做什么…
What are you...
给我另一边
Give me that.
离合器！离合器！离合器！
Clutch! Clutch! Clutch!
- 右转 - 不，左转
- Turn right. - No, left.
是谁在骑？快！
Who's driving? Come on!
离合器
Clutch!
左转…
Left! Left!
后面有多少车跟来？
How many back there?
我看不到，等等
I can't see. Hold on.
你在做什么？
What are you... What?
- 别想歪 - 我没想过
- Don't get any ideas. - I'd never dream of it.
一台…不，两台
One... No, two.
- 利用那些桶子 - 什么？
- Go for the barrels. - What?
非常好
Very good.
抓紧
Hold on!
我们走上面
Let's take the highway.
- 直升机！ - 好，别太兴奋
- Helicopter! - All right, keep your shirt on.
- 到后座去 - 你想要保护我？
- Get on the back of the bike. - Are you trying to protect me?
不，我需要平衡摩托车，到后座去
No. I need to balance the bike. Get on the back.
- 准备好了吗？ - 好了
- You ready? - Yeah.
走！
Go!
放开离合器
Pop the clutch.
它在我们后面
It's behind us.
快让开！
Move!
让开！
Get out of the way!
你看到直升机吗？
You see the chopper?
我看不到，等等
I can't see. Hold on.
你又在…
What are you...
我们被困住了
Trapped.
绝不会
Never.
你能拿肥皂给我吗？
Would you pass the soap?
在那里
Over there.
你甩钩子的技巧不错
You were pretty good with that hook.
因为我出身恶劣的居住环境
It comes from growing up in a rough neighborhood.
你骑摩托车的技术不错
You were pretty good on the bike.
因为我从没长大
Well, that comes from not growing up at all.
这里，让我来
Here. Allow me.
别动歪脑筋，邦德先生
Don't get any ideas, Mr. Bond.
我想起来，我们或可联手
Just off the cuff, I thought we might link up.
携手合作？
Work hand in hand?
彼此更接近
Stick closer to each other.
或许我们可一起对付张将军
Maybe we go after General Chang together.
轮到你了
Your turn.
谢谢你帮我洗头发
Thanks for washing my hair.
我喜欢独自行动
I work alone.
幸好我刚好经过
Lucky for you I stopped by.
我本可以自己解决他的
I could've taken care of him.
但你没有
But you didn't.
耳环给我
Give me the earring.
中国军方标准用枪
Copy of a Makarov 59. Standard issue, Chinese Army.
看起来张将军想杀你
Looks like General Chang wants you dead.
你仍认为你能独自行动？
You still think you can do this alone?
那要看你的任务是和平的或是想报复
It depends whether your mission is peace or revenge.
我的任务是要制止战争
This is about stopping a war.
去年我们发现一些隐形材料…
Last year we found stealth material was missing...
在张将军的基地失踪了
from one of General Chang's bases.
我追查线索到卡佛的汉堡总部
I followed a lead to Carver's headquarters in Hamburg.
隐形材料？
Stealth material?
我们以为他要做隐形飞机
We thought he was building a stealth plane.
不对，是一艘隐形船
No. Stealth boat.
那是他们唯一能接近得文夏号的方法
That's the only way they could get close to the Devonshire...
所以他们才能钻开导弹室
so they could drill inside the missile room.
记得吗？他们偷走了军舰上的导弹
Remember? They stole a cruise missile from that ship.
他说将时间表提前到午夜
He said he was moving the timetable forward to midnight.
对，他当然会这么做
Yes, of course he did.
他会利用黑夜，将船停靠在…
Under cover of darkness he'll position the stealth boat...
接近英国舰队的地方
near the British fleet...
然后向中国发射导弹
fire the missile into China.
- 如此我们两国就会展开报复 - 卡佛就能大肆报导
- And we will retaliate. - And Carver will provide the pictures.
- 我必须警告北京 - 不
- I have to warn Beijing. - No.
警告中英双方政府，让他们去谈
Let's warn both our governments, get them talking.
这样我们就有时间能找到船
It'll give us time to find the boat.
站起来
Stand up.
真有家的感觉
Hmm. It's just like home.
你提供设备，那就我来发信
You get the equipment, I'll send the messages.
再仔细想想
On second thought...
还是你来打字好了
you type.
首先，我们得先找到船
First we find the boat.
归属张将军管辖的所有港口跟海口…
Of all the harbors and inlets controlled by General Chang...
有22点人口密集地区
22 are in highly populated areas.
剩下14点能让他藏匿隐形船
That leaves 14 where he could hide a stealth boat.
白天一定能看到它
You can see it during the day.
雷达探测不到，但肉眼一定能看到
It's invisible to radar, but not the human eye.
非常新奇
Very novel.
他一定将船藏在…
He'd have to hide it someplace...
能在一晚内往返得文夏号的地方
where he could sail to the Devonshire and back in one night.
这个看起来好熟悉
This looks familiar.
我们做了一些改良
We've made some improvements.
真的吗？
Have you, indeed?
好的，往返共八小时
Okay. Four hours out and four hours back.
我们可以假设船速三十海里
Let's assume the boat is traveling at a speed of 30 knots.
我一向都很崇拜中国的科技
I've always been a fan of Chinese technology.
根据电脑显示
According to this...
有四个地方能让他停靠那艘船
there are four places where he could harbor the boat.
小心你的左边
Up on your left.
查询看看那个地区有无可疑之处
Run a cross check on those areas for anything suspicious.
新型华特枪
Ah, the new Walther.
我已跟Q博士要求一支
I asked Q for one of these.
我找到了，你来看看
I've got it. Look.
四艘船失踪，三艘因不明原因下沉
Four missing boats. Three unexplained drownings.
这一定就是了
That has to be it.
哈隆湾
Ha Long Bay.
他对那个岛很了解
He knows the island.
他说在黄昏时船只驶近那里会很危险
He says that it's dangerous for boats to be around there at sunset...
但为了五千元美元
but for 5,000 American dollars...
他会带我们去
he'll take us.
很好
Good.
或许他愿意收支票
Maybe he'll take a check.
这是个沉闷的例行公事
It's mostly dull routine, of course...
但偶而能有机会在迷人的黄昏出海
but every now and then you get to sail on a beautiful evening like this...
有时跟腐败的西方势力的情报员合作
and sometimes work with a decadent agent of a corrupt Western power.
大家都说共产主义者不懂享乐
And they say Communists don't know how to have fun.
我不想让你感到失望
I hate to disappoint you...
但我连毛语录都没有
but I don't even have a little red book.
如果我有不测
If anything happens to me...
水雷的引线在这里
the fuses for the mines are in here.
我们会一起完成任务
We're gonna finish this together.
如果我可以这么说的话，你找到了一位…
And if I may say so, you found the right...
合适的腐败的西方情报员…
decadent, corrupt Western agent...
为工作伙伴
as a partner.
- 看到隐形船了吗？ - 还没
- See the stealth? - No.
越来越晚了，这是附近最后一个海湾
It's getting late and this is the last cove in the bay.
找到了
Yeah, that's it.
设定时间十分钟
Set the timers for ten minutes.
应该有足够时间让我们在船爆炸之前离开
That'll give us time to get out of here before the ship explodes.
就算它没沉也会显示在雷达上
Even if it doesn't sink, it'll show up on radar.
- 我们的舰队会完成工作 - 如果他们收到我们发出的信
- Our fleets will finish the job. - If they got our message.
- 你上去，移到那边 - 好的
- Okay, you, up and over. - Okay.
我们已在舰队之间
We're in position between the fleets.
向双方舰队旗舰各发射一枚导弹
Fire one missile at the flagship of each fleet.
中国会以为英国耀武扬威
The Chinese will think the British are rattling the saber...
而英国会以为中国好战
the British will think the Chinese are being belligerent...
这时媒体就可提供精彩客观的报导
and the media will provide cool, objective coverage.
开始破坏行动
Let the mayhem begin.
英国舰队皇家比德福号
被导弹锁定目标
Missile lock-on.
通知海军总部“特遣舰队受到导弹攻击”
Send a signal to the Admiralty: "Task group under missile attack. "
警报控制系统报告有米格21号机
Sir, AWACS reports two waves of land-based MIG 21s inbound.
第一批将在两分钟内出现在雷达荧幕上
The first group should be on our screens in two minutes.
还有多久米格机就会在英国舰队射程范围内？
How long before the MiGs are within firing range of the British fleet?
12分钟
Twelve minutes.
我雇用你来干嘛的？
What the hell do I pay you for?
如果她在那里，邦德也在那里
If she's there, Bond is there.
史丹博，去找他们
Stamper, find them.
林葳…有摄影机！
Wai Lin! Wai Lin! Camera!
她敢动一下，就杀了她
If she blinks, kill her.
你跟我来
You come with me.
史丹博呼叫驾驶台，邦德已死了
Stamper to Bridge. Bond is dead.
太好了
Delicious.
要确保清除所有的水雷，将那个女的带来见我
Make sure you clear all the mines, and bring the girl up to me.
你确定要带她上来？
Are you sure you want her up here?
这是我的事
It's my business, Mr. Gupta.
我喜欢有观众
I like an audience.
林小姐
Ah, Miss Lin.
你的同胞真合作
Your countrymen are being so cooperative...
很急切的想要挽回面子
so predictably eager to save face.
我的政府知道你在这里，他们正在找你
My government knows you're out here. They're looking for you.
据我们的雷达显示
Not according to our radar...
你们的米格机快要攻击英国舰队
where it seems your MiGs are about to attack the British fleet...
还有多久的时间？
in how many minutes?
再九分钟就在射程范围内
Nine minutes to firing range.
就算他们正在找我
And even if they were looking for me...
可是我们在隐形船上
we're on a stealth boat.
他们看不见我，甚至你…
They can't see me, or you...
或是你的朋友…
or even your friend...
死去的邦德中校
the late Commander Bond...
他这时正沉下南中国海底
who is at this moment on his way to the bottom of the South China Sea.
他是我的新主播
He's my new anchorman.
真可怜
Pathetic.
到底发生了什么事？
What on earth's going on?
007发出的信息
A message from 007...
也经中国情报主管证实
just confirmed by my opposite number in China.
“要求舰队搜寻一艘雷达几乎侦测不到的隐形船”
"Tell the fleet to search for a ship that's almost invisible to radar. "
敌人不是中国
The Chinese aren't the enemy.
卡佛愚弄了我们双方
Carver's been playing both sides for fools.
将军，从海军总部发出的急电
Admiral, sir, urgent message from the Admiralty.
你看这个
Look at this.
在雷达上侦测到任何小东西吗？像是救生艇或潜望镜吗？
Anything on radar that looks very small? Lifeboat, periscope, anything?
- 没有，长官 - 隐形船？他们一定疯了
- No, sir. - Stealth boat, sir? They have gone mad.
林小姐，你将看到的不只是导弹攻击
What you're about to witness, Miss Lin, is not so much a missile attack...
而是一个新时代的诞生
but the launch of a new world order.
五分钟后，你的同胞就会攻击英国舰队
In five minutes, after your countrymen have attacked the British fleet...
那时候我将会帮英国报复
I shall retaliate for dear old England...
把导弹射向北京
by sending this missile into Beijing...
就是张将军跟其他高级官员
where General Chang has just called an emergency meeting...
召开紧急会议的地方
of the Chinese high command.
不幸的是…
Unfortunately...
张将军因为交通挤塞将会迟到
General Chang will be delayed in traffic...
会在其他领导人毙命后到达
arriving just after the missile has killed your leaders...
他来不及阻止空军击沉英国舰队
and too late to stop the air force from sinking the entire British fleet.
但是他将会接管中国政府与英国谈判停战
But he will be just in time to take over the government, negotiate a truce...
摇身一变成为一个世界领袖
and emerge as a world leader...
还会获得诺贝尔和平奖
with a Nobel Peace Prize.
- 你可以得到什么？ - 我？
- And what do you get? - Me?
什么也没有
Oh, nothing.
只有未来一百年，中国的独家电视广播权
Just exclusive broadcasting rights in China for the next hundred years.
已经准备好攻击
Ready to rock and ruin.
林小姐，请恕失陪，我有工作需要去完成
If you'll excuse me, my dear, I have something of a deadline to meet.
准备发射导弹
Prepare for the missile launch.
古达先生
Mr. Gupta.
你好，艾利欧
Hello, Elliot.
很有趣的计划
Interesting plan.
但是我有一些属于你的东西
But I think I have something of yours.
德国人的办事效率真高
So much for German efficiency. Mr. Stamper.
- 迟些才杀他 - 不要开枪
- Don't shoot him yet. - Hold your fire.
邦德先生，欢迎参观这次世界危机
Welcome to my world crisis, Mr. Bond.
公平的交易
Even trade, Elliot.
古达换林葳
Gupta for Wai Lin.
没有他你无法发射导弹
You can't fire the missile without him.
而且你好像抗拒不了我拥有的女人
And it seems you can't resist any woman in my possession.
你还在等什么？射死他
What are you waiting for? Shoot him!
我已说了我们会一起完成任务
I told you we're going to finish this together.
真的非常浪漫
Oh, how romantic.
你了解你现在的情况多荒谬吗？
Do you realize how absurd your position is?
可没有你为了增加收视率而发动战争那么荒谬
No more absurd than starting a war for ratings.
伟人都是利用媒体去拯救世界
Great men have always manipulated the media to save the world.
威廉赫斯特曾对他的摄影师说
Look at William Randolph Hearst, who told his photographers...
“你提供照片，我提供战争”
"You provide the pictures, I'll provide the war. "
我只是先跨一步
I've just taken it one step further.
很抱歉
Sorry about that.
我刚才有点分心
I tuned out there for a moment, Elliot.
太可惜了？
Touch?
古达先生
Mr. Gupta...
导弹准备好发射没有？
is the missile ready to fire?
一按下按钮，北京就会消失
Press the magic button, Beijing disappears.
看来你活得比你的合约长
Then it seems you've outlived your contract.
我有个备用计划
You see, Mr. Bond, I have a backup plan.
我也有
Uh-huh. So do I.
他炸开了船身，雷达将会侦测到我们
He's breached the hull. They'll see us on radar.
长官，我们收到一个在水面上微弱、间断的讯号
Sir, we have a small, intermittent contact on the surface.
在方位112度标绘出来
Plot the bearing 1-1-2 degrees.
讯号很微弱，但我发誓几秒前它不在雷达上
It's a very weak signal, but I'd swear it wasn't there a second ago, sir.
通知舰队先别向中国发动攻击
Yeoman, tell all ships not to fire on the Chinese for any reason whatsoever.
通知中国舰队指挥官
Send the message to the Chinese fleet commander:
“发现不明船只”
"Have sighted unknown ship... "
快将火扑灭！
Get those fires out!
下去保护导弹
Get down there and protect the missile.
史丹博，杀了那两个王八蛋
Oh, and Mr. Stamper, would you please kill those bastards?
做得好
Nice work.
他们正在加速
They're speeding up.
- 我们必须停止它 - 你能解决引擎室吗？
- We have to stop the boat. - Can you take care of the engine room?
- 当然 - 好，做完后快离开船
- Of course. - Good. Do it and get off the ship.
我要去阻止导弹
I'm going to stop the missile.
中国舰队指挥官发出的信
Signal from the Chinese fleet commander.
“致皇家海军特遣舰队”
"To Royal Navy Task Group:
“我们的雷达也出现不明船只”
We also have the unknown ship on our screens.
“除非它向我们攻击，否则我们将不会开火”
We will not fire unless it turns toward China.
“它交由你们处理”
Until then, she's yours. "
“无论那是什么，将它击沉”
Now, Captain, whatever the hell that thing is, sink it.
好的，回音是否太弱无法瞄准？
Right, sir. Is that echo too weak for missile lock?
- 是的 - 好吧
- Yes, sir. - Right.
我们采取传统的方法
We'll do it the old-fashioned way.
邦德让我们变成目标
Bond turned us into the target.
他也一起陪葬
Along with himself.
准备迂回行动
Take evasive action.
立即准备导弹倒数
Prepare the missile countdown immediately.
开始发射程序，倒数五分钟
Initializing launch sequence. "T" minus five minutes and counting.
倒数五分钟
"T" minus five minutes and counting.
他们时速48海里
Uh, sir, they're making 48 knots.
两分钟后便超出射程范围
They'll be out of range in two minutes.
继续开火，拖慢他们
Keep firing. Slow them down.
引擎失灵，我们坐以待毙，引擎室
The engines are out. We're sitting ducks here. Engine room.
跟我来！
Follow me!
倒数四分钟
"T" minus four minutes and counting.
做的好，最高速度
Well done. Officer Watch, increase max.
继续开火！
Keep firing!
每个人，弃船
All hands, abandon ship.
弃船
Abandon ship.
史丹博，你要怎么处置那个女的？
Mr. Stamper, what are you doing about the girl?
或许你该去引擎室看看
Perhaps you'd consider looking in the engine room.
倒数三分钟
"T" minus three minutes and counting.
你又来迟了一步
You're too late again, Mr. Bond.
这是你的坏习惯
It's a bad habit of yours.
你无能为力了
There's nothing you can do.
倒数两分钟
"T" minus two minutes and counting.
导弹已输入程序
The missile's fully programmed.
不能制止了
It can't be stopped.
我的计划很快就会成功
In minutes my plan will succeed.
感谢你的努力
Thanks largely to your efforts...
英国海军会毁掉证据
the British Navy will destroy the evidence...
我会离开这里，乘着卡佛新闻直升机…
and I'll be out of here in a Carver news helicopter...
作报导
covering the event.
将会是很精彩的节目
It's going to be a fantastic show.
我可能有个突发新闻要告诉你
I may have some breaking news for you, Elliot.
你忘了大众传播的第一守则
You forgot the first rule of mass media, Elliot...
满足人们的需要
Give the people what they want.
倒数一分钟
"T" minus one minute and counting.
扔掉
Drop it, Mr. Bond...
否则扔了你的朋友
or I drop your friend.
全都结束了，史丹博
It's over, Stamper.
放了她
Let her go.
只是你跟我
Not between you and me.
试用雷管，导弹会引爆
James, try the detonators. The missile will set them off.
别跟女性争辩，她们通常都对
Never argue with a woman. They're always right.
倒数四十秒
"T" minus 40 seconds.
为卡佛报仇
For Carver!
还有高夫曼
And Kaufman!
我欠了你一次痛苦的死亡
I owe you an unpleasant death, Mr. Bond.
倒数二十秒
"T" minus 20 seconds.
我们一起死
We die together, Mr. Bond.
倒数十秒
"T" minus ten seconds.
三
Three...
二、一
two... one...
M，比德福号报告卡佛跟船一起下沉
M, Bedford reports Carver went down with the ship.
似乎邦德成功了
Seems that Bond made it.
莫尼彭妮，请你写下
Moneypenny, take this release.
艾利欧卡佛失踪了，怀疑他是坐他的…
Elliot Carver is missing, presumed drowned...
豪华游艇在南中国海附近溺毙
while on a cruise aboard his luxury yacht in the South China Sea.
目前当地警方相信…
At present the local authorities believe...
该位媒体大亨是自杀的
the media mogul committed suicide.
邦德中校
Commander Bond...
林上校
Colonel Lin...
这是英国皇家比德福号
this is the H.M.S. Bedford.
你们在那里吗？
Are you there?
他们正在找我们
They're looking for us, James.
我们再隐藏一会儿吧
Let's stay under cover.
将此片献给艾伯特库比布鲁克里